Guide to the Department of Landscape Architecture design problems, 1924-1940.
Department of Landscape Architecture design problems,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Department of Landscape Architecture design problems, 1924-1940.
15-5-1433
Cornell University. Department of Landscape Architecture.
1 cubic ft., 4 map case drawers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Exchange problems between Cornell and other universities, and landscape problems set by Bryant Fleming and Eugene D. Montillon; survey data and planting plans, 1908-1921; student projects, 1913-1931; student work for the American Academy in Rome by Edward Lawson, R. E. Griswold, and others; files on New York State institutions used as study data, 1898-1933; plans and measured drawings of historic estates by E. Gorton Davis, 1914-1929.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Exchange problems between Cornell and other universities, and landscape problems set by Bryant Fleming and Eugene D. Montillon; survey data and planting plans, 1908-1921; student projects, 1913-1931; student work for the American Academy in Rome by Edward Lawson, R. E. Griswold, and others; files on New York State institutions used as study data, 1898-1933; plans and measured drawings of historic estates by E. Gorton Davis, 1914-1929.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Fleming, Bryant.; Montillon, Eugene D.; Lawson, Edward G. (Edward Godfrey), 1884-1968.; Griswold, Ralph E. (Ralph Esty), 1894-1981.; Davis, E. G. (Edward Gorton), 1880-; American Academy in Rome.; American Academy in Rome
Subjects:
Landscape architecture -- Study and teaching.; Landscape architecture -- Study and teaching
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Design Problems, Survey Data
Series II. Students' Work
Series III. Student Work of and for the American Academy in Rome
Series IV. New York State Institutions
Series V. E. Gorton Davis and others
Series VI. Measured drawings of Italian villas
Series VII. Other Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Design Problems, Survey Data
  - Survey data landscape design problem, Expression (Folder 2)
  - Survey data landscape design problem, 1921 (Folder 2)
  - Landscape design problem survey, 1921 (Folder 2)
  - Design problem department LA rural community center, 1912 (Folder 2)
  - Planting details problem 8, Undated (Folder 2)
  - Township of Gouverneur, NY, CULA dept., 1913 (Folder 3)
  - Township of Gouverneur, Undated (Folder 3)
  - Survey data design problem, 1916 (Folder 2)
  - Senior design problem survey data, 1916 (Folder 2)
  - Senior, junior, and sophomore design sketch problems, 1914-1921 (Folder 5)
  - Planting plan with prices from Eastern Nurseries, Jamaica Plain, Mass and Bay State Nurseries, North Avington, Mass, EE Long, 1916 (Folder 2)
  - Recreation Park outline planting plan Problem 3 Course 17, Undated (Folder 2)
  - Survey data sketch senior design problem Ward "Hillside" Wyoming, NY, Undated (Folder 2)
  - Planting plan for J.H. Robertson, Detroit, Michigan. Problem 2 course 17, Undated (Folder 2)
  - Study data plot plan relocation of roads, Rome Custodial Asylum, NY, 1914 (Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Buttermilk Wading Pool Project, Undated (Folder 4)
  - Survey data Cascadilla Creek, 1908 (Folder 2)
  - Survey data Six Mile Creek, 1910 (Folder 2)
  - Survey of Six Mile Creek watershed, Undated (Folder 2)
- Series II. Students' Work
  - Bryant, M.W, 1916 (Folder 8)
  - Cooley, C.R., 1922 (Folder 8)
  - Clarke, G.D., 1913 (Folder 8)
  - Davis, F.A., 1916 (Folder 7)
  - Davis, L.W., Undated (Folder 9)
  - Faulhaber, F.A., Undated (Folder 8)
  - Fuller, J.E., 1919 (Folder 7)
  - Gardner, J.C., 1921 (Folder 8)
  - Griswold, R.E., 1916 (Folder 6, 8)
  - Halsted, R.M., 1916 (Folder 8)
  - Hartjoy, Jr., 1916 (Folder 8)
  - Hoffman, A.P., 1916 (Folder 8)
  - Huls, R.T., 1922 (Folder 9)
  - Lister, J.M., 1931 (Folder 6)
  - Merrill, H.A., 1922 (Folder 8)
  - Newton, N.J., Undated (Folder 7)
  - Raymore, H.B., 1916 (Folder 8)
  - Sandford, H., 1921 (Folder 9)
  - Schultheis, Henry, Undated (Folder 9)
  - Spalding, Helen, 1916 (Folder 8)
  - Strong, H.H., Undated (Folder 7)
  - Tapscott, K.A., 1917 (Folder 6, 7)
  - Tonow, P.T., 1921 (Folder 7, 9)
  - Wiedorn, W.S., 1919 (Folder 7)
  - Survey of Cayuga Lake, 1913 (Folder 9)
  - Suggested development of entrance to Cascadilla Gorge, 1926 (Folder 9)
  - Unidentified, Undated (Folder 9)
- Series III. Student Work of and for the American Academy in Rome
  - Lawson, Edward. Villa Gamberaia at Settignano, Planting plan, Undated (Folder 10)
  - Lawson, Edward. Villa Medici at Rome, Undated (Folder 10)
  - Griswold, R.E., Smith, F.M., White, S. Submission for competition fellowship at the American Academy in Rome, 1920 (Folder 10)
  - Doorway of Papa Guilio by Vignola, Undated (Folder 10)
  - Villa Torlonia Frascati, 1922 (Folder 10)
- Series IV. New York State Institutions
  - Delhi Agricultural School, 1914-1915 (Folder 11)
  - Bathouse on Eastern State Parkway, Undated (Folder 12)
  - Morrisville School of Agriculture, 1911 (Folder 11)
  - Mount Morris hospital for the treatment of tuberculosis, 1933-1935 (Folder 11, 12)
  - Newark school, Undated (Folder 12)
  - New Paltz school, Undated (Folder 12)
  - Oxford Women's Relief Corps Home, 1898 (Folder 12)
  - Map of the State of New York showing the Improved Highways and many points of historic interest, 1916 (Folder 12)
- Series V. E. Gorton Davis and others
  - Ahles, R.L. location survey, East Williston LI, 1916 (Folder 14)
  - Comstock, Professor J.H. Ithaca, NY, 1914 (Folder 14)
  - Littlejohn, R.M., LI, 1917 (Folder 14)
  - Munson Edgar Planting Plan, Williamsport PA, 1917 (Folder 14)
  - Rathbone, J. Arnot, Elmira, 1914 (Folder 14)
  - Grand Lodge Home and Orphanage Group Plan, 1920 (Folder 13)
  - Grampian, house at, Williamsport PA, 1927 (Folder 13)
  - Illustration various arrangements of planting, Undated (Folder 14)
  - Arrangement for small town property, Undated (Folder 14)
  - Untitled survey drawing, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Property of Mrs. AW Sumner, Moorestown, NJ, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Master Development plan, Blue Ridge parkway and parks, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Plan of a garden, after the garden of Mrs. Herbert Pratt, Glen Cove, LI, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Plan of a small property, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Annapolis, Md. Rideout House, Undated (Folder 14)
    Measured by: E.G. Davis
  - Ashland, Lexington KY, Res. Of Henry Clay, 1919 (Folder 13, 14)
  - Babbit House, Bristol, RI, Undated (Folder 14)
  - Brandon on the James River, VA, Undated (Folder 14)
    Measured by: C.F. Gillette, E.C. Jones
  - Cambridge, MD, old res., 1929 (Folder 14)
  - Fredericksburg, VA, Martha Washington House, sundial from, 1929 (Folder 14)
  - Fredericksburg, VA, Colonel Fielding Lewis 1749, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Georgian House, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Hampton, NY, box garden, Undated (Folder 14)
    Measured by: C.C. Talman Architect Auburn
  - Laurens Ante-Bellum property, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Lower Brandon, James River, VA, 1922 (Folder 13)
  - Manice Estate Queens, LI, 1830, 1922 (Folder 14)
    Measured by: J.V.L.
  - Marmion near Shiloh, King George County, VA, 1672, 1922 (Folder 14)
  - Middleton Place on the Ashley near Charleston, SC, 1925 (Folder 13)
    Measured by: W.B. Gerhart
  - Myrtle Grove, Easton, MD, Undated (Folder 14)
  - New Castle, Delaware, George Read Res., 1929 (Folder 14)
  - Oxmoor Estate of the Bullitt family, Jefferson KY, 1929 (Folder 14)
    This drawing was used in an article by E. Gorton Davis entitled "An Example of Early American Landscape Architecture", in American Landscape Architect, December 1929
  - Port Royal, VA, old res., 1929 (Folder 14)
  - Ratcliffe Manor, Easton, MD, 1922 (Folder 14)
    Measured by: E.A. Piester
  - Sabine Hall, Warsaw, VA, 1922 (Folder 14)
  - Shirley Plan of a Colonial Estate on the James River, VA, 1915 (Folder 14)
  - Stratford, VA, 1922 (Folder 14)
  - Sylvester Manor, 1744, Undated (Folder 13, 14)
  - Westover, Roxbury, VA, sketch plan of on the James River, 1922 (Folder 14)
    Measured by: E.G. Davis and others
- Series VI. Measured drawings of Italian villas
  - Villa Palmieri Florence, 1921 (Folder 14)
    Measured by: Raymond W. Blanchard
  - Villa Plinina Lake Como, 1922 (Folder 14)
  - Peretti Palace, Rome, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Villa Medici Roma, 1909, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Stucco details in bedroom Pompeii, 200 BCE, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Villa Cicogna, Undated (Folder 13)
  - Garden bed plans, Undated (Folder 1)
- Series VII. Other Material
  - Portrait of Olaf Brauner, Undated (Mapcase-folder Frame 1)